Lacey Collection 1880's-1890's Ms B52 Ms B52
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Lacey Collection 1880's-1890's
1858-1896
Ms B52
Fairfield Museum and History Center
1.75 Linear feet
This collection contains items pertaining to schools in the Plattsville section of Fairfield, CT including text books, record books and photographs.
(4 boxes, 175 items, 1 oversize items)
Lacey, Charles C., d. 1962
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Custodial History note
This collection was donated by Robert Lacey (L92.Nov.14).
Scope and Contents note
These papers deal mostly with schools in the 1800's. Box I contains photographs, North District bills and records books, and miscellaneous papers from Hoyden Hill School. Box II contains records books, workbooks, tests and town flyers. Boxes III and IV contain text books.
Biographical/Historical note
The Lacey's in this collection were from Plattsville in the northeast corner of Fairfield. They were involved in education and politics.
Lacey, M. B.; Lacey, Robert; Penmanship; Plattsville (Conn.); Schools--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Textbooks.
- Box I, 6.0 folders
  - Photographs of schools and classes, Folder A; 15.0 items
  - North School District bills, late 1800's, Folders B and C; 80.0 items
  - Record books North District School, 1858-1891; Folder D; 2.0 items
  - Hoyden's Hill School miscellaneous papers, late 1800's, Folder E; 25.0 items
  - General correspondence to M. B. Lacey, 1890's, Folder F; 10.0 items
- Box II, 5.0 folders
  - Penmanship books by Charles C. Lacey, 1889; Folder A; 15.0 items
  - Math workbook, Folder B; 1.0 item
  - Fairfield Record book; School Record book, 1882-1883, 1894-1896; Folder C; 2.0 items
  - Miscellaneous education papers, Folder D; 10.0 items
  - Test pages of Ada Golding and Mamie Burr; Curriculum guides, Folder F
- Text Books, Box III; 8.0 items
- Text Books, Box IV; 6.0 items
- Town flyers, 1891; 4.0 items (Oversize Manuscript Box 1)